<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christopher Negrich</title>
    <link>http://cnegrich.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Christopher Negrich</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 16:28:45 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://cnegrich.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ConstrictPy</title>
      <link>http://cnegrich.github.io/projects/ConstrictPy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 16:28:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cnegrich.github.io/projects/ConstrictPy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ConstrictPy is a python tool that implements the ConstrictR package. ConstrictPy handles all the input and output, provides a UI, and data visualization that ConstrictR lacks. ConstrictPy is designed to be extremely user friendly and requires minimal technical skills to use effectively. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Currently in development, full release of ConstrictPy is planned for August 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ahoetker/ConstrictPy&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConstrictR</title>
      <link>http://cnegrich.github.io/projects/ConstrictR/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 16:28:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cnegrich.github.io/projects/ConstrictR/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ConstrictR is an R package inspired by a paper by Lionel Guidi designed for microbiome analysis. However, since it is just a package of useful bioinformatical analysis functions, it can be applied to a wide variety of data. The philosophy behind the project is to make an R package that is as user friendly as possible. We want a use of any experience level to have access to more complicated mathematical analysis techniques. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
ConstrictR is currently a work in progress with plans on the full version being available in August 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cnegrich/ConstrictR&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://cnegrich.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:59:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cnegrich.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float: right;position: absolute; top: 150px;right: 380px;width: 200px;height: 200px;border-radius: 50%;overflow: hidden;&#34; src=&#34;ChrisProfilePic.jpeg&#34;&gt;
Christopher Negrich &lt;br /&gt;
Github: &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cnegrich/&#34;&gt;cnegrich&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
LinkedIn: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-negrich/&#34;&gt;Christopher Negrich&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Email:   &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:cnegrich@gmail.com&#34;&gt;cnegrich@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honors Bachelors of Science in Mathematics awarded May 2018&lt;br /&gt;
Barrett Honors College at Arizona State University, Tempe, Arizona&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;experience&#34;&gt;Experience&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Informatics Team Leader&lt;/strong&gt;  from August 2017 - Current &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The Biodesign Institute at Arizona State University&lt;/strong&gt;, Tempe, Arizona&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead a development team currently working on ConstrictR and ConstrictPy bioinformatics tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and built an R package (ConstrictR) and an accompanying Python tool (ConstrictPy) to assist in common bioinformatical analysis techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Package and tool focus on usability on the front-end (in Python) and mathematical efficiency and accuracy on the back-end (in R)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed the software version using Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on preparing professional materials for publication of work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cyber Operations, Analysis, and Research Intern&lt;/strong&gt; from May 2017 - August 2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Argonne National Laboratory&lt;/strong&gt;, Lemont, Illinois&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Position funded by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and authored a semi-passive TCP/IP vulnerability scanning tool based on open-source intelligence techniques, utilizing emerging techniques in the field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Field tested and deployed a full feature version of the semi-passive scanner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilized Python to design an object oriented framework for web scraping, including a fully featured user interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leveraged natural language processing, regular expressions, keyword searching for data handling/presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Researched a technical advisory covering best practices for personal area network (PAN) security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neuroscience Research Intern&lt;/strong&gt; from July 2015 - December 2016 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The Biodesign Institute at Arizona State University&lt;/strong&gt;, Tempe, Arizona&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease and Traumatic Brain Injury (TBI) research project using both mouse and human tissue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applied image analysis and statistical quantification techniques to confocal fluorescent microscopy to determine disease progression and pharmaceutical treatment effectiveness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed internal protocols for common fluorescent microscope staining techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisted in editing and producing a variety of materials including professional posters and papers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Informatics Research Intern&lt;/strong&gt; from September 2014 - April 2015 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Arizona State University&amp;rsquo;s School of Life Sciences&lt;/strong&gt;, Tempe, Arizona&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Researched the divergence of the Y chromosome from the X chromosome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created file generators in Python and Java for automation and data validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisted in the education of lab scientists on tool usage and introductory programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;technical-skills&#34;&gt;Technical Skills&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Administrator level experience with&lt;/strong&gt; Linux: Debian, Ubuntu (including LTS) Arch, Kali, Buscador, Black Box, Parrot Security, Windows: Home, Professional, and Server, and Mac OS: Personal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proficient coding ability in&lt;/strong&gt; Python [2.7, 3.5, 3.6], C/C++, Java, JavaScript (JS), Structured Query Language (SQL)[MySQL, Sqlite, postgresql], HTML, CSS, PHP, R, Bash, Windows PowerShell, Assembly (x86), Clingo, Cplus2ASP, Wolfram Mathematica, and Matlab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience with common data science tools&lt;/strong&gt; including Pandas, Numpy, Matlab, Mathematica, and Orange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience with common security tools&lt;/strong&gt; including Nmap, Burp, Nessus, Maltego, Wireshark, Ettercap, Hashcat, Gnome Privacy Guard (GPG). OpenSSL, OpenVPN, and Tor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience with databases&lt;/strong&gt; both SQL-based and non-SQL-based such as MongoDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code base management experience with&lt;/strong&gt; GitLab, Github, and the software development lifecycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware familiarity with&lt;/strong&gt; Desktops, Laptops, Servers, Raspberry Pi, Routers and Modems (Office and Home networking)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>http://cnegrich.github.io/posts/Introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cnegrich.github.io/posts/Introduction/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a recent college graduate from the Barrett Honors College at Arizona State University (ASU) with a Bachelors of Science in Mathematics who is very interested in data science, tool development and cybersecurity. During my time at ASU, I worked on several different research projects mostly focused on computer science and software development, but also including work in both wet labs and cybersecurity. Although my degree is in mathematics, I spent my time focusing on applying it to computer engineering and cryptography. I have also taken most of the core courses for computer science students including algorithms and all of the base language courses. I am proficient in numerous coding languages including Python [2.7, 3.5, 3.6], C/C++, Java, JavaScript (JS), Structured Query Language (SQL)[MySQL, Sqlite, postgresql], HTML, CSS, PHP, R, Bash, Windows PowerShell, Assembly (x86), Clingo, Cplus2ASP, Wolfram Mathematica, and Matlab. And have experience with common data science tools, common security tools, popular Python, Java, C, and R packages/libraries, and database management. Additionally, I have experience with agile and the software development lifecycle and code base management software including GitLab and GitHub. I also have hardware familiarity with desktops, laptops, servers, Raspberry Pi, routers and modems (Office and Home networking). Finally, I have administrator level experience with Linux: Debian, Ubuntu (including LTS) Arch, Kali, Buscador, Black Box, Parrot Security, Windows: Home, Professional, and Server, and Mac OS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;current-research&#34;&gt;Current Research&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I am leading a software development team in creating an R package (called ConstrictR) and an accompanying python tool (called ConstrictPy). We will be releasing a full feature, tested version of these projects in the upcoming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christopher Negrich &lt;br /&gt;
Github: &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cnegrich/&#34;&gt;cnegrich&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
LinkedIn: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-negrich/&#34;&gt;Christopher Negrich&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Email:   &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:cnegrich@gmail.com&#34;&gt;cnegrich@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>