<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Logical Fallacies on Chris Negrich</title><link>/tags/fallacies/</link><description>Recent content in Logical Fallacies on Chris Negrich</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/fallacies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bad Reason Fallacy</title><link>/posts/fallacies/bad_reason/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fallacies/bad_reason/</guid><description>Overview The bad reason fallacy is a formal logical fallacy that comes from arguing a conclusion is bad because a reason for it is bad. This is a fallacy since the conclusion can be true despite being providing a false argument.
Fallacy Names Bad reason fallacy Structure Proposition A because of the argument B. B is false, therefore the proposition A is false.
If A then B because C.</description></item><item><title>Post Hoc Fallacy</title><link>/posts/fallacies/posthoc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fallacies/posthoc/</guid><description>Overview This logical fallacy comes from assuming sequential events cause one another.
It should be noted that this fallacy is highly similar to two other fallacies. First, the fallacy of the inverse. If the latter half of the statement is negated, the post hoc fallacy becomes a fallacy of the inverse. Second, the fallacy of affirming the consequent, if A then B; B, therefore A.
Fallacy Names False attribution fallacy Post hoc fallacy This name comes from a Latin phrase &amp;lsquo;post hoc ergo propter hoc&amp;rsquo; which translates to &amp;lsquo;after this, therefore because of this&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Affirming a disjunct</title><link>/posts/fallacies/disjunct/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fallacies/disjunct/</guid><description>Overview Affirming a disjunct is a logical fallacy that occurs in propositional logic when a disjunct is assumed. The logical operator or is inclusive, meaning it can be A or B or both. This fallacy occurs when a disjunct is assumed. That is the assumption of the terms A implies not B and B implies not A.
Fallacy Names Affirming a disjunct Structure Given A or B.</description></item></channel></rss>